CINDY MASTRY: In this clip, Faith is going to help me demonstrate a really great way to release tension and stretch your shoulders using the strap.
So I'm going to give Faith a strap, then she's just going to stand with her feet about a little bit wider than hip-width distance apart, and she's going to reach her arms up and try to find a "V." Good.
So we're going to ask her to rotate on the diagonal just a little bit.
Good.
She's going to drop her hands down and place them next to her hips keeping that same width and tension on the strap.
Because she's going to inhale, reach the arms up to the sky, dropping her shoulders out of her ears and placing her shoulder blades down her back.
And then she's going to take the strap back behind on her exhalation so dropping it all the way down to her hips.
Good.
And notice how that opens up her chest, opens up her shoulders.
Inhaling, lifting her arms up to the sky, and as she exhales bringing them back down to her hips.
Good.
Widening her shoulder blades away from each other.
Inhale, reaching the arms up to the sky; exhale, opening up through her shoulders, through her rotator cuff and dropping the arms down behind.
Good.
Inhaling, lifting them up, breathing your spine long as you do so, and exhaling, dropping her shoulders down.